Guide to the Isaac Ingalls Stevens Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Isaac Ingalls Stevens Letter to M.[?] F. Schmidt. (WA MSS 444), 1859 March 18; 1
  The third series of the Isaac Ingalls Stevens Papers (WA MSS 444) consists of a letter (a single page) written by the Governor to M[?] F. Schmidt on March 18, 1859. The letter contains instructions as to the chapter headings in the "Geographical Memoir," which is part of Stevens' Narrative and Final Report of Explorations for a Pacific Railroad, Washington, 1860 (U.S. War Dept. Reports of Explorations and Surveys, 1860, Vols. XII-XIII).
  - Stevens, Isaac Ingalls, 1818-1862. ALS to M[?] F. Schmidt. St. Nicholas, New York, March 18, 1859. 1 page., 1859 March 18 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Letter regards formatting for publication of a "geographical memoir." Mentions Schmidt's interview with General Lane.
- Map of Washington and Nebraska Territories (WA MSS 445), [1857 April]
  The fourth series of the Isaac Ingalls Stevens Papers (WA MSS 445) consists of a map which is mounted on linen and folded. The map is entitled "Prepared in the Office of Explorations & Surveys, War Department, from a Map of the Indian Nations and Tribes of the Territorys of Washington and Nebraska west of the mouth of the Yellowstone. Made under the direction of Isaac I. Stevens, Gov. of Wash. Terrt. & Supt. of Ind. Affairs" [April, 1857]. The map consists of the engraved map of the region from the Rocky Mountains to Puget Sound, prepared by Governor Stevens for his report on the survey for a Pacific railroad, with information added in manuscript about the Indian tribes and reservations, settlements, and military posts. There is a manuscript extension east of the Rocky Mountains to the Yellowstone River to show the more eastern tribes, and, inserted in the lower left corner in place of the original caption and part of Oregon, two tabular statements of the Indians west and east of the Cascades, showing "tribes, population, parties to the several treaties, reservations provided in the treaties, and temporary encampments," as well as "Notes of the Indians of the Territory of Nebraska between the Rocky Mountains and the mouth of the Yellowstone."
  A month before Governor Stevens was relieved as superintendent of Indian affairs by Colonel James W. Nesmith, he sent a letter and map of the Indian nations and tribes of the Territory of Washington and of the Territory of Nebraska, with tabular statements and notes, to George W. Manypenny, Commissioner of Indian Affairs, April 30, 1857. The region from the Cascades to Fort Benton has been printed on a reduced scale, with much less detail, in Hazard Stevens, Life of Isaac Ingalls Stevens, 1900, I, facing p. 16, and the "Tabular Statements" and "Notes" appear as the Appendix to Vol. I, pp. 503-505, from the original on file in the Indian Bureau. The Miller map is a copy made for the Secretary of War.
  - Map: "Prepared in the Office of Explorations & Surveys, War Department, from a Map of the Indian Nations and Tribes of the Territorys of Washington and Nebraska west of the mouth of the Yellowstone. Made under the direction of Isaac I. Stevens, Gov. of Wash. Terrt. & Supt. of Ind. Affairs.", [1857 April] (Box 3 (Broadside))
    Map. 125 x 63 cm. Mounted on linen and folded. Original leather binding (no longer present) stamped in gold, "Indian tribes of Washington and Nebraska. Secretary of War."
    The map consists of the engraved map of the region from the Rocky Mountains to Puget Sound, prepared by Governor Stevens for his report on the survey for a Pacific railroad, with information added in manuscript about the Indian tribes and reservations, settlements, and military posts [90 x 63 cm.]; a manuscript extension east of the Rocky Mountains to the Yellowstone River to show the more eastern tribes; and, inserted in the lower left corner in place of the original caption and part of Oregon, two tabular statements of the Indians west and east of the Cascades, showing "tribes, population, parties to the several treaties, reservations provided in the treaties, and temporary encampments"; and "Notes of the Indians of the Territory of Nebraska between the Rocky Mountains and the mouth of the Yellowstone." A month before Governor Stevens was relieved as superintendent of Indian affairs by Colonel James W. Nesmith, he sent to George W. Manypenny, Commissioner of Indian Affairs, April 30, 1857, a letter and map of the Indian nations and tribes of the Territory of Washington and of the Territory of Nebraska, with tabular statements and notes. The region from the Cascades to Fort Benton has been printed on a reduced scale, with much less detail, in Hazard Stevens, Life of Isaac Ingalls Stevens, 1900, I, facing p. 16, and the "Tabular Statements" and "Notes" as the Appendix to Vol. I, pp. 503-505, from the original on file in the Indian Bureau. The Miller map is a copy made for the Secretary of War.